<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<game>
	<title>Mystic Melee</title>
	<release-date>May 4, 2017</release-date>
	<website>http://mysticmelee.com/</website>
	<press-can-request-copy>TRUE</press-can-request-copy>

	<platforms>
		<platform>
			<name>PC / Steam</name>
			<link>http://store.steampowered.com/app/454770/</link>
		</platform>		
	</platforms>
	
	<prices>
		<price>
			<currency>USD</currency>
			<value>TBD</value>
		</price>
	</prices>

	<description>
	Mystic Melee is a physics-based platformer where you play as one of four wizards fighting to save the galaxy. Gameplay features a variety of imaginative elemental spells and an acrobatic movement system. The game includes a single-player campaign spanning five worlds and 50+ levels, as well as local multiplayer modes for up to four players.
	</description>
	
	<history>
	Mystic Melee began as a physics-based platforming experiment with multiplayer in mind. While inspired by the "platform-fighter" genre, Mystic Melee developed a unique focus on platforming as opposed to fighting mechanics. That focus was emphasized by the signature multiplayer mode called "Hypersphere", which is played like a spell-slinging version of basketball. Objective-based multiplayer allowed for a variety of spells with uses other than just damaging opponents.
	
	With lots of fun spell and movement mechanics, the game deserved a single-player mode that explored their uses. With a large number of possible interactions between spells, map features, and the physics engine, the single-player campaign became a full experience. The design of the single-player levels were inspired by speedrunning-focused games like Super Meat Boy and Dustforce. It was a natural fit with the fluid movement mechanics and spells that offer extra mobility.
	
	About a year into development, the indie game studio Serenity Forge became interested in publishing the game. With their partnership, the game's characters and universe were further developed. The game is being prepared for initial release in Spring 2017. Following plans include completing and releasing online multiplayer capabilities built into the game.
	</history>

	<features>
		<feature>Single player campaign with over 50 levels to hone your platforming and spellcasting skills. Top the leaderboards and compete with friends for the fastest runs!</feature>
		<feature>Multiplayer matches with objective-based modes have you controlling artifacts or scoring on an enemy goal, rewarding mastery of both combat and platforming.</feature>
		<feature>Unique elemental spells that reward strategy and skill. Crush, slice, and incinerate your opponents with summoned rock golems, whirling leaf attacks, and volcanic strikes.</feature>
		<feature>Fluid physics-based platforming that's easy to learn and hard to master. Wall-jump, slide, and dash to outmaneuver enemies and complete challenges.</feature>
	</features>
	
	<trailers>
		<trailer>
			<name>World 2 Preview</name>
			<youtube>iEyG1yysQ0I</youtube>
		</trailer>
		<trailer>
			<name>Alpha Video</name>
			<youtube>sOb_2qxxmbw</youtube>
		</trailer>
		<trailer>
			<name>Announcement Trailer</name>
			<youtube>uHEDt1QqAlk</youtube>
		</trailer>				<trailer>			<name>Interview with Chase Bethea of Gamer Complainers</name>			<youtube>KQA2ZgTuXNU</youtube>		</trailer>
	</trailers>
	
	<awards>
		<award>			<description>EVO Indie Showcase - Mystic Melee @ The Mix</description>			<info>EVO Championship Series, Las Vegas, July 15, 2016</info>		</award>
	</awards>
		<!--
	<quotes>
		<quote>
			<description>This is a rather insignificant quote by a highly important person.</description>
			<name>Person Name</name>
			<website>Website</website>
			<link>http://</link>
		</quote>
		<quote>
			<description>An extremely positive quote from a rather insignificant person. Also great.</description>
			<name>Some Guy</name>
			<website>This Page Is Visited By 12 Visitors A Month</website>
			<link>http://</link>
		</quote>
		<quote>
			<description>I pretend to love this game even though I do not actually understand it.</description>
			<name>Pretentious Bastard</name>
			<website>Artsy Page</website>
			<link>http://</link>
		</quote>
		<quote>
			<description>HOLY SHIT SO AMAZING</description>
			<name>Caps Guy</name>
			<website>Angry Review</website>
			<link>http://</link>
		</quote>
	</quotes>
	
	<additionals>
		<additional>
			<title>Original Soundtrack</title>
			<description>Available for free from</description>
			<link>http://somemusicsite.com/thislink</link>
		</additional>
		<additional>
			<title>Release Blog Post</title>
			<description>The blog-post through which this game was released is available at</description>
			<link>http://vlambeer.com/bloglink</link>
		</additional>
	</additionals>-->
	
	<credits>
		<credit>
			<person>Ben Hopkins</person>
			<role>Game Designer, Developer, Pixel Artist, Sound Design</role>
		</credit>
		<credit>
			<person>Zhenghua Yang</person>			
			<website>www.serenityforge.com</website>
			<role>Producer, Serenity Forge</role>
		</credit>
		<credit>
			<person>Kevin Zhang</person>			
			<website>www.serenityforge.com</website>
			<role>Producer, Marketing Director</role>
		</credit>
		<credit>			
			<person>Caleb Montoya</person>			
			<website>www.serenityforge.com</website>		
			<role>Character Art, Story Development</role>
		</credit>
		<credit>
			<person>Max Messenger Bouricius</person>			
			<website>https://soundcloud.com/gerlacus</website>
			<role>Music, Freelancer</role>
		</credit>
		<credit>
			<person>Matthew DeJonghe Wright</person>
			<website>http://www.shivelights.com/</website>
			<role>Music, Freelancer</role>
		</credit>
	</credits>
</game>